Steven Tolson

OVERVIEW

Highly experienced senior IT professional with over twenty years in the industry working across financial services, retail, healthcare, and government sectors. Proven deep technical and leadership skillset gained from designing and managing large environments and leading the implementing of both private and public cloud (AWS, Azure and GCP) hosted enterprise solutions. Comfortable communicating and influencing at all levels from the boardroom to project stakeholders, engineers and end users.

KEY SKILLS

- Technical Leadership
- Microsoft Azure
- Google Cloud Platform
- Cloud Security
- Core Services (DHCP, DNS, NTP)
- Solution & Enterprise Architecture
- Amazon Web Services
- Tooling & Automation
- Windows and Linux administration
- Scripting (Bash, PowerShell, Python)

EXPERIENCE

Technical Infrastructure Architect

February 2018 to Present

John Lewis Partnership

Primary responsibilities include designing infrastructure, platform, hosting and technology service solutions to meet business requirements. Promoting the use of common technology across the organisation and pursuing cost savings through efficient designs, reference architectures, secure reusable patterns and technology roadmaps. Highlights of the projects I have played a prominent role in include:

- Design and deployment of Azure and GCP public cloud platforms
- Deployment of multiple applications onto public cloud using laaS/PaaS/Kubernetes platforms
- Design of data platform on GCP public cloud utilising Big Data product suite
- Design of Ansible Tower environment for public and private cloud automation
- Development of DevOps automation toolset; GitLab, Ansible Tower, Terraform, Jenkins, KMS
- Strategic road maps for hosting and public cloud technologies

Within the architecture domain I run a successful initiative to mentor members of the platform teams to get involved in architecture work and input into strategy for their specialist areas. I also run a public cloud working group that involves architects and engineers from across the organisation meeting weekly to input into the development of our public cloud hosting offerings.

Infrastructure Design Consultant

February 2016 to February 2018

Prudential Plc.

My role in the Project Design function focused on technical infrastructure design for cloud and onpremise projects. I researched products and solutions, ran early stage proof of concept workshops, defined reference architectures and produced high and low level designs taking them through the appropriate review and approval processes. During implementation phase I often took a hands on approach, taking the role of Technical Lead before passing over to the Operational teams.

The following is a list of the most high profile projects I was involved in during this role:

- Design and build of the Office365/Azure Cloud Identity solution
- Design and build of Microsoft Azure enterprise hybrid cloud environment
- Design and build of Amazon Web Services (AWS) enterprise hybrid cloud environment

- Design and deployment of multiple service lines into Azure and AWS environments
- Definition of Cloud Design Principles and associated reference architectures
- Design of Splunk Enterprise environment

A recognised subject matter expert (SME) and working group lead for core services (Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, ADFS), automation (Orchestrator and Puppet) and public cloud (AWS and Azure) technologies. This involved leading groups of engineers to improve the architecture of the platforms and define the future roadmaps.

Wintel Design Specialist

May 2008 to February 2016

Prudential Plc.

Responsible for detailed designs for new technologies, upgrades and improvements to existing solutions in the Wintel space. I provided technical leadership during project implementation, authoring of support documentation and ran handover workshops to bring support staff on-board with new products. Along with many business unit specific application implementations the following is a selection of projects I led during my time in this role:

- Design and build of DevOps automated Windows and Linux server-provisioning environment
- Design and build of AD Federated Services SSO infrastructure
- Definition of on boarding process for SaaS solutions (Salesforce, ServiceNow, Adobe AEM..)
- Design of VMware and Hyper-V server virtualization environments
- Upgrade of multi-forest Active Directory environment to Windows Server 2008 and 2012
- Design and implementation of Infoblox enterprise DNS, DHCP, IPAM and NTP solution
- Design of System Centre Configuration Manager and Orchestrator environments.
- Planning and resource for large-scale data centre migrations

During my time in this role I had the honour of acting as mentor to two apprentices who joined the IT area, one of whom went onto secure a fulltime role within the organisation.

Virtual Infrastructure Specialist

May 2007 to May 2008

BUPA

Responsible for the management and support of the global Wintel server estate. Tasked with driving forward the implementation of automation virtualization technologies I was responsible for the successful delivery of the following projects:

- Design, installation and management of Citrix and VMware ESX server environments
- Automation of all Windows Server, VMware ESX & Citrix XenApp server builds
- Business continuity planning and testing for Active-Directory, VMware, Citrix & SQL
- Creation of scripts to automate tasks and improve service resiliency
- Creation of high quality design and implementation documents for all

Server Systems Specialist

October 2003 to June 2007

WLMHT NHS Trust

Responsible for the design and support of the Trusts server infrastructure which was hosted across four hospital sites. The following is a breakdown of my primary responsibilities:

- Day-to-day management and support of the Trust server infrastructure
- Management of core network services (Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, WINS)
- Design, installation and management of Citrix and VMware ESX environments
- Management of WSUS patching and McAfee ePO virus protection infrastructures
- Management of server backups and DR planning

Earlier IT career history to 1995 available on request.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

I have achieved the following technical qualifications during my time in the industry:

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Azure Cloud Platform
- Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer
- VMware Certified Professional
- Citrix Certified Administrator
- Certified Infolbox Core Engineer
- ITIL Foundation Level
- CompTIA Network+

Ten GCSE's including: A in Maths, six B Grades (including English and the Sciences)

PERSONAL DETAILS

Location: Eversley, Hants Telephone: 07846 714878

Email: steventolson@yahoo.co.uk